Tajmir khan

Date of birth: 03/02/1994 | **Nationality:** Pakistani | **Phone number:** (+92) 3085299701 (Mobile) | **Email address:**

tajmirkhan515@gmail.com | Email address: tajmirkhan@cs.qau.edu.pk | LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/tajmir-khan-a60a6b174 | **Github:** https://github.com/Tajmirkhan515/ | **Portfolio:**

https://tajmirkhan515.github.io/ Address: 23370, Rustam, Pakistan (Home)

ABOUT ME

As an NLP researcher have good publications in reputable journals and substantial teaching experience. Recently, have taught Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) Lab at Quaid E Azam University and have strong coding skills, showcased in my GitHub repository. Additionally, I have experience in blogging (OOP). Besides, I participated in international hackathons. Looking ahead, I am keen on continuing my research and publishing in esteemed journals.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

08/2019 - 19/04/2022 Islamabad, Pakistan

M.PHIL COMPUTER SCIENCE Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad

Address 45320, Islamabad, Pakistan | Website https://qau.edu.pk/ | Field of study Computer Science | Final grade 3.42/4 |

Thesis Multimedia Vertical Web Search Query Modification Framework using Relevance Feedback Approach

01/11/2015 - 20/03/2018 Nowshera, Pakistan

MCS COMPUTER SCIENCE Northern University

Address 24110, Nowshera, Pakistan | Website http://www.northern.edu.pk/ | Final grade 3.45/4 |

Thesis Tailor Management System (Android App)

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/01/2024 - CURRENT Islamabad, Pakistan

LAB INSTRUCTOR OF OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING (OOP) QUAID-I-AZAM UNIVERSITY

- Taught Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) lab sessions to a class of 50 BSCS students.
- Implemented and demonstrated OOP concepts through practical exercises using Visual Studio.
- Evaluate the students using tasks, correct their errors, and provide feedback to enhance learning.

30/09/2017 - 29/08/2019 Peshawar, Pakistan

APPLICATION DEVELOPER LEAP APP SOLUTION

I worked as an Android developer.

PUBLICATIONS

2024

End-to-end pseudo relevance feedback based vertical web search queries recommendation approach

Journal: Multimedia Tools and Applications - Springer;

Impact Factor 3.6

Tajmir Khan 1, Umer Rashid* 2, Abdur Rehman Khan 3

Link https://github.com/Tajmirkhan515/Queries-Recommendation

2024

End-to-end pseudo relevance feedback-based vertical web search queries recommendation Software

Journal: SoftwareX - Elsevier 2024;

Impact Factor 4

Tajmir Khan 1, Umer Rashid* 2, Abdur Rehman Khan 3, Naveed Ahmad 4, Mohammed Ali Alshara 5

Link https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352711024002425?via%3Dihub

2024

Faceted Aggregated Multimedia Search Results Exploration Framework [Under Evaluation]

Abdur Rehman Khan, Taimir khan, Umer Rashid

INTERNATIONAL HACKATHONS

19/07/2024 - 21/07/2024

llama-3-hackathon

Recently submitted a complete project (VisisonAI) app developed using Python and Django. In this project, I worked as an AI/ML engineer and was responsible for integrating the entire application. Similarly, uploaded my GitHub repository.

Links https://lablab.ai/u/@tajmirkhan515923/ cm0fh47v0008ve7ih12mw6dxf

26/07/2024 - CURRENT

Falcon Hackathon

Actively engaged in the Falcon international hackathon, focusing on AI/ML and learning Streamlit. Additionally, I am leading the project and overseeing its development.

DIGITAL SKILLS

python | c++ | Android Developement (Android Studio, Java) | SQL (MySQL) | machine learning | Natural Language Processing (NLP) | java

RECOMMENDATIONS

Dr. Umer Rashid Supervisor

Dr. Umer Rashid is an Assistant Professor at the School of Computer Science at the Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan. His research interest is in Multimedia Information retrieval.

Email umerrashid@gau.edu.pk | Phone (+92) 5190642012

Link http://cs.gau.edu.pk/profiles/umer.htm

Dr. Rabeeh Ayaz Abbasi Head of the Department

Dr. Rabeeh Ayaz Abbasi is an Associate Professor at the School of Computer Science at the Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan. His research Social Network Analysis.

Email rabbasi@gau.edu.pk | Phone (+92) 5190642050

Link http://cs.qau.edu.pk/profiles/rabeeh.htm